Hello friends, welcome to the channel. Today it is
available at a 30% discount from its
peak and it can potentially generate 40%
returns. In this video, we will do a very
simple technical analysis of the
stock and we will also see
how the fundamental business of the company is,
their quarterly numbers, profit
and loss account statement, share holding
pattern, all this, we will understand in detail the
symptoms of the technical analysis. If you will
notice one thing here, right now this company is
trading below its 50 and 200 moving averages. Number one, if
you look here, if we
draw the support and resistance line here, then
if you will notice here that at
1100, this company has a very good support.
It is at the 1300 level, hence it shows a lot of resistance. To
go above 1300, the
second resistance that this stock
particularly shows is at the 1400
level, that is, if you look at the last 1 year  If we
look at the chart, this stock is
moving in the range of 1400 to 1100. Well,
here we get the opportunity to do two swing trades, between 112,
1300,
240. If we enter here
and exit here, then
your return here is 18%. If you
enter here and exit here, then
your return is
27%.
Here is a swing trading thing. In
fact, if you look at this company in the last one and a half years, then
this pick was made at the
level of 1650. If we look at the level of 1650
here, then this stock is currently available to
us at a discount of 32%.
Simple theory says that if the company
fundamentally has
earnings growth quarter on quarter year, then the
stock price of the company
follows the earnings, that is,
in simple language, it means that the earnings are
directly proportional to the company.  If we look at the
price, it
means that if the
fundamentals of the company are sound, then this stock will definitely
touch the 1650 level from here.
Neither you nor I know when it will do so,
but definitely in the next 23 years,
if there is a good bull run to see, then
it will definitely touch the 1600 level.
This means that the growth you get here will be
40% from this level.
That is why we will now
look at the fundamentals of the company in the hidden mixtape.
What is the fundamentals of this company, what is its business like,
how does it collect revenue, how does it
earn and how much is its profit,
what is its future like? So first of all, we will
open the screener and
understand the fundamentals of the company. The
market cap of the company is greater than 55000.
If we look at the P of the last five years here, then there are
two very
interesting things here. First of all, the company is
only doing blue red on its medium as of today. As of
today, its  There are bills of p305
and the medium P for the last five years has been
46.4. This is the number value. The
second important thing that you will see is that
P is decreasing but their earnings, this
app, this blue chart, this
app is
growing consistently, the
company has been rated.
Okay, right now here we
see the quarterly performance of the company,
if you see here, the
revenue from December 2019 to
December 2022 has almost doubled, which
means there is no problem
in the top line in sales.
Secondary income,
operating profit has also been almost same in two
quarters. If you
see here, mainly because of Covid, there was a lot of
cleanup in Covid.
This date was an important reason for this company to be
rated as an insurance company.
If you see the net profit over every
quarter, they have done very
-very. Right now we see their panel statement,
if you see here  The top
line, which is what we call sales,
revenue, from 2011 till
date, they have increased their revenue six
times,
which is above Rs 17,000 crore as of today.
Similarly, operating profit is
growing, in fact,
their net profit is also growing.
If we look at their metrics here, that
too over 10 years, five year
time period, then they have seen a very, very high
sales growth of 16% in the last 10 years, and this has
also been replicated in the profit, however,
this thing has not been reflected in the stock price.
And you should notice that
if the company has profit, if the company has profit, then
definitely if the company's profit
increases, then it definitely has an
impact on the share price. Now,
if you look at their share holding pattern here,
mutual funds have made their bike investment here in the
last few quarters.  I have accumulated a lot
and high on this particular sector and this
particular company, we have
understood that fundamentally there is no problem in this company.
Now let us
see here how this company does business.
Now we understand here what is basically a
general insurance company.
Before that, we should understand that
two companies operate in the insurance sector,
one is life insurance company and one is
non-life insurance company. This
non-life insurance company is the
general insurance company.
What are the things in non-life insurance,
like your motor insurance, your
health insurance, which is not related to life,
that whole group is
under general insurance.
If you look here, usually the
public sector companies, like
public sector banks, if
we look at them, then 40% of their
profits are
in the hands of only a few private players. If you look here, the three
largest companies of the space  Inside that is
ICICI Lombard Allianz and HDFC
EGO, they account for one third of the profit of that sector
and why is this so, we will understand a very
important terminology which is there
in general insurance which is called flood
gas, it is very important for you to understand this, so
what is flat basically, flat means
how much fund the company has and the
fund is invested in different entities at different
places, where can they
invest, they can invest in equity, they can invest
in equity share market, they can invest
in bonds or they can
invest in different government securities and by investing here
they earn a profit and
this profit is
added to their core operating profit, here
if suppose any non-life
insurance company, if underwriting profit is
on tax, the meaning of underwriting profit is very
simple that suppose any
insurance company is collecting its
premium by selecting the correct premium and
commission and where is their expense
Firstly, their total management
expense would be operating expense,
plus the claims they basically give,
so these are particular expenses. If
their premium is greater, then the
expense of underwriting profit,
if their profit is high, then
basically it gets added to the float.
Correct, here we will see an interesting
thing that
if you
look here, the investment
and assets of non-life insurance companies are usually 11x. Compare to life
insurance, you will see here and how they are
increasing. Here, the
investment assets of general insurance companies are
much higher than those of life insurance companies.
Now we understand
why we should invest in this company. The
first reason is strong support
from the parent company. This company is backed by
ICICI Bank, so they have a very
good balance and are very
well diversified across
different insurance companies. However, their majority
of the business comes from these.  It is
from motor insurance and other insurances
SEBI earns a good amount of money and every
insurance is also very profitable. If you
notice one thing here, in 2019,
crop insurance was 17%, their product mix.
This has reduced over the period of years.
Why has it reduced? Management had
given guidance that this particular crop
insurance was not in profit
or should I say that their profit
margins were low here, so over the
period of years, they have deliberately reduced their market
share here
and they have expanded their business in other places.
If you see, this thing
is big in fire insurance and health insurance. One
more thing is that they have a very strong
underwriting, proper profit and level.
Financially they are a very sound company. If you
value any insurance company, that
insurance
company is getting more premium
earning and their expenses are low. If the same
thing happens above 100%, which means
that the company is always investing money in claims. Rather than  The
most important thing here from their premium is
that ICICI's
combined ratio is 100% close to zero, which is not what would come
from a good bond, but all this
is relative. How other companies in this space
compare to them matters a lot.
If you talk about public sector
companies here, their average combined
ratio is 130. If we talk about Ajay Bhai,
who is an insurance
company of Buff, his ratio was 110. In 2019
solvency ratios, solvency ratio
means how the company will be able to repair its long term debt,
whatever its long term debt is. This is the
only
thing, it means that here as of
today, its ratio is 2.9, which is very low.
If you look here, currently the
stock trades at the
level of 1340, from here its target
price is ₹16. Your
return of close to 40% and
investment horizon should be  If you think that
my money will double in between 6 months, in 3 months, in a year, then
you will only
get disappointment. You will only be disappointed.
If your intention is to
build a good corpus over a long term, then
definitely this company can give you a good return. So here is
a
simple to understand or detailed fundamental
SLS technical analysis of ICICI Lombard General Insurance Company. If you
liked my video, then please like
this video and subscribe to the channel. I am
Ashish Shining of, thank you so much.